doverpublications.com 2019-07-17

# Dover Books | Dover Publications | Dover Publications Privacy Policy

Last updated 4/23/12

Customers have trusted Dover Publications Inc. ("Dover Publications") to protect their privacy for over fifty years. Whether you've been buying books from us since 1948 or are new to the Dover family, rest assured we plan to earn your trust every day. It's also the reason we've created this Privacy Policy for DoverPublications.com. We want you to understand what information we collect and what we will—and won't do with it. By visiting DoverPublications.com you agree to accept the practices described in this Privacy Policy. View our Corporate LSC Communications [Privacy Policy](http://www.lsccom.com/privacy).

##### What Information Does Dover Publications Collect About Customers?

We gather information so that we can improve and personalize your shopping experience with Dover Publications. Information that we collect falls in to four primary categories.

  * **Information that Customers Give Us:** We receive and store the information that you enter at our website, provide to us on an order form from one of our catalogs, or give to us in any other way. You can always choose not to provide some or all of the information we ask for, but this may prevent you from using some of our website's features. When you choose to provide information, we will use it for purposes that include: fulfilling your orders, responding to your inquiries or requests, customizing our websites for you, improving our stores and catalogs, and communicating with you.
  * **Automatic Information:** Whenever you interact with Dover Publications, we receive and store certain types of information. For example, we use "cookies" to obtain information when your web browser accesses this website. This information helps us to customize and personalize our interaction with you. This Site is hosted by Yahoo! Store. Yahoo! hosts the store pages, ordering system, and order data. Yahoo! Automatically collects order information but may only use this information in the aggregate. If you access this store through Yahoo! Shopping, Yahoo! Also automatically collects information about your shopping experience. Please see the Yahoo! Privacy Policy for more information about how Yahoo! uses this information.
  * **Email Communications:** In order to make the email we send you more helpful and relevant to your interests, we receive and store certain types of information. For instance, if your computer supports this functionality, we may receive a confirmation when you open an email we send you. We may also receive a confirmation when you follow a hyperlink from one of our email messages to our website. If we receive customer lists from other companies, we compare them to our customer lists in an effort to avoid sending duplicate messages to the same customer and to help ensure that our customers will find the messages we do send interesting and useful. If you want to stop receiving email from us, simply use the Unsubscribe link found in any message or contact [privacy@doverpublications.com](mailto:privacy@doverpublications.com).
  * **Information Provided by Other Sources:** In an ongoing effort to improve our products, services and communications, we may receive and store information about you from other companies. For example, we may use information from other sources to personalize our website for you or to send you a special offer or product recommendation that we think you'll like. We may also receive updated address and delivery information from our shippers or other sources, which enables us to correct our records and helps to ensure accurate and timely delivery of your orders and communications such as print catalogs.
  * **Third-Party Web Beacons:** We use third-party web beacons from Yahoo! to help analyze where visitors go and what they do while visiting our website. Yahoo! may also use anonymous information about your visits to this and other websites in order to improve its products and services and provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by Yahoo!, [click here](https://reports.web.analytics.yahoo.com/optout,OptOut.vm?domain=a.analytics.yahoo.com).

##### Cookies

_What's a cookie?_ A cookie is an alphanumeric identifier, which we transfer to your computer via your Web browser and store on your computer's hard drive (don't worry about disk space, our cookies are tiny files). The cookie file allows us to recognize your computer when you visit our website so that we show you things that you saved in your Shopping Cart on your last visit and present products or offers on our website that we think you'll like.

On most web browsers you will find a "help" section on the toolbar. Please refer to this section for information on how to receive notification when you are receiving a new cookie, and how to turn cookies off. We recommend that you leave cookies turned on because they will enable you to take advantage of some of our websites best features.

##### Does Dover Publications Share the Information It Receives?

We are not in the business of selling information about our customers. We consider this information to be a vital part of our relationship with our customers and we treat it with great care and respect. There are, however, certain limited circumstances in which we may share customer data with certain third parties, as set forth below.

  * **Agents:** Dover Publications, like many companies that serve consumers, hires other companies to perform certain functions. Examples include mailing catalogs, delivering packages, sending postal mail, sending email, processing credit cards and removing duplicate information from our customer lists. When we employ another company to perform a function of this nature, we only provide them with the information they need to complete the task and they are not allowed to use that information for any other purpose.
  * **Promotional Notices:** On very rare occasions we may contact our customers about a product or service provided by another business. If we contact you in this way, it will only be to provide you with information about a business that we're convinced you'll like. If we do this, the only communication you receive will be from us and we will not give business information about you, such as your name, postal or email address.
  * **Business Transfers:** As we develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses, stores or assets. In transactions such as these, customer information is generally one of the transferred business assets. Moreover, in the unlikely event that Dover Publications or one of its publishing lines are acquired, customer information may be one of the transferred assets.
  * **Protection of Dover Publications and Others:** We may release account and other personal information when we believe that such release is appropriate to comply with law; protect the rights of, property or safety of our users, Dover Publications or others; or enforce our Terms of Use and other agreements. In addition, we may exchange information with other organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

##### How Secure Is Information About Me?

  * Information that you input is protected during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts the information you input.
  * We do not reveal your credit card number when we confirm an order. Naturally, we do transmit your credit card number to the appropriate credit card company when we process an order from you.
  * You should protect against unauthorized access to your password, your account and your computer by logging out when you finish using a shared computer or a computer that is easily accessed by others.

##### Access to Information About You.

If you desire to review your own personal information, to correct existing information, or to remove your information, please contact Dover Publications via email at privacy@doverpublications.com. If you request removal of your personal information, you acknowledge that residual information may continue to reside in Dover Publications' records and archives, but Dover Publications will not use that information for commercial purposes. Dover Publications reserves the right to maintain your personal information if Dover Publications has suspended, limited, or terminated your access to our website for violating the Dover Publications [Terms of Use](https://www.doverpublications.com/terms).

##### What Choices Do I Have?

As outlined in this Privacy Policy, you can always choose not to provide information, however, doing so may prevent you from placing an order or accessing other valuable features at our website.

##### Links to Third Party Sites

You may be able to access third party websites through links available on this Site. You understand and agree that your use of such third party sites will be governed by the privacy policies of those sites and not by this Privacy Policy. Dover Publications shall not be responsible for the actions of the operators of such third party websites.

**Exclusions** Any submissions that you make to any public areas of our website such as bulletin boards or product reviews ("Public Areas") will be public and will not be subject to this Privacy Policy. Dover Publications does not control, and is not responsible for, the actions of other users of the web site with respect to any information you post in Public Areas. Any personally identifiable information that you post in a Public Area can be read and used by other visitors to the Site. In addition, information that you submit to Public Areas may be collected and used by others to send you unsolicited messages and for other purposes. Finally, product reviews are powered by a third party and are subject to a Usage Agreement and the Terms of Use and Privacy Policy of PowerReviews.com.

**Children** Dover Publications sells terrific products for children, but does not sell products for purchase by children. We sell children's products that may be purchased by adults and the use of our Site is limited to adults 18 years of age and over. Dover Publications does not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children's Internet use and to help enforce our Privacy Policy by instructing their children to never provide information on this website without their permission.

**Terms of Use, Notices, and Revisions** If you choose to visit DoverPublications.com or any web sites owned or controlled by Dover Publications, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Policy and our [Terms of Use Agreement](https://www.doverpublications.com/terms), including limitations on damages and application of the law of the State of New York. If you have a concern about privacy at our websites, please send an email with a detailed description of your concern to [privacy@doverpublications.com](mailto:privacy@doverpublications.com) and we will try to resolve it. Our business and website change constantly. The Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy may change also. Our use of information that we receive and store is subject to the Privacy Policy and Terms of Use in effect at the time of our use of such information. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post the revised Privacy Policy on this website.

This site is hosted by Yahoo! Store. Yahoo! hosts the store pages, ordering system, and order data. Yahoo! automatically collects order information but may only use this information in the aggregate. If you accessed this store through Yahoo! Shopping, Yahoo! also automatically collects information about your shopping experience. Please see the [Yahoo! Privacy Policy](http://privacy.yahoo.com/privacy/us/) for more information about how Yahoo! uses this information.
